<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>KMSTRUBE.NET</title>
    <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on KMSTRUBE.NET</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:32:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.kmstrube.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASIW I spent $500 on a Windows 98 Gaming PC</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:32:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://techhub.social/@kmstrube81/113630797779004684&#34;&gt;posted to Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; back in December about playing the original Half-Life for the first real time on PS2. Finally experiencing one of the greatest FPS games of all time was a revelation. So much so that I went out and installed it on my &amp;ldquo;gaming&amp;rdquo; PC right away. I needed to play it again the way God intended. With a keyboard and mouse. I wanted more Half-Life and wanted to play the expansions now. I barely knew of their existence prior to this. I could just get them on Steam, I think they are like $5 a piece. But if you’ve read my work before, you know it’s never that simple…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Half-Life</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;act-0-black-mesa-inbound&#34;&gt;Act 0: Black Mesa Inbound&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 5 years old, my family got our first home computer. The year was 1997. The computer was a Sony VAIO. I didn’t have a clue what a computer was at the time. When Dad booted up the computer that first time, I heard the Windows 95 boot up chimes, I saw the intro sequence of the VAIO-space software, and I was hooked. (Between the chimes for Windows 95 booting up and the iconic MacOS9 chime, the 90s truly had the most memorable startup sounds of all time)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Legend of Zelda- Link&#39;s Awakening</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My letter to Santa Claus when I was 6&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog12/image1.png&#34;&gt;
This was my letter to Santa Claus in 1998. While I can’t remember whether I got twisted metol or my front teeth or the golf course material, I’ll never forget waking up on Christmas Morning and seeing a blue Game Boy Pocket under the tree. That Game Boy came with two games, Super Mario Land 2 and Donkey Kong Land 3 (so lovingly referred to as Donkey Kong Crountry). I played that Game Boy until the buttons wore out. Game Boy was famous for ports and reimagining of console games, such as the two aforementioned games. Not only just famous for ports, but also for taking risks that Nintendo was unwilling to take on their home console games.
&lt;img alt=&#34;A screenshot from our home movies that year&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog12/image2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I hosted my blog on Google Sites</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 Update: I have since moved my blog to Github pages using Hugo with the PaperMod theme. The content of this post remains true, but note that I no longer rely on Google to host my content and use hacks to make RSS work. Someday I will write a follow up post on the move to Hugo and will link it here&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been something of a tinkerer. In high school and college, it was messing around with the game files of Call of Duty and Call of Duty: United Offensive to create multiplayer mods for myself and my friends. This might sound hard to believe, but in the late 00s and early 10s; Stack Overflow wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite the repository of knowledge it is today. When I had issues making the game run the exact way I wanted to, tinkering with my code or configs line-by-line is all I had. I consider it a blessing more than a curse, I learned a lot about coding and networking this way.
&lt;img alt=&#34;Call of Duty:UO Box Art&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog11/image1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Legend of Zelda- A Link to the Past</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was a certified Zelda hater as a kid. The game didn&amp;rsquo;t really appeal to me. You have to fight with a sword and not a gun? Why does Zelda look like Mini-Me dressed up like Peter Pan? I gave the original a try on my dad&amp;rsquo;s NES and couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where to go after the first dungeon. I was much more drawn to the fast pace of side scrolling games such as Super Mario Bros and Donkey Kong Country. Legend of Zelda was one of those &amp;ldquo;boring medieval fantasy games” like Mystic Quest, Final Fantasy, or Chrono Trigger (just some of the most highly regarded games of all-time; yeah my tastes weren&amp;rsquo;t that great). Soon the 16 bit era would give way to the 3D revolution and Nintendo would fall out of favor with me for Playstation. And though I would be back on Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s bandwagon the following generation with the Gamecube, I never found myself giving the series a shot.
&lt;img alt=&#34;An animated Triforce from the Link to the Past title screen&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog10/image1.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide: How to update to the latest version of a ROM Hack in Afterplay.io</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ROM hacking community is one of the coolest parts of the larger retro gaming community. ROM hackers are passionate fans of retro games that use their programming, art, and creative skills to create brand new levels, graphics, or even whole new experiences from our favorite games. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/6&#34;&gt;In a previous guide,&lt;/a&gt; I showed how to use your iPhone to patch a retro game into a ROM hack using the JS Patcher and the original ROM and patch file. Often ROM hacks will release updates with even more new content or features. Many times your old save data from the previous version is still valid and you can continue on your adventure using the updated patch. If you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://afterplay.io/&#34;&gt;Afterplay.io&lt;/a&gt; to keep your ROMs and saves in sync on all your devices, follow this guide to help you update your ROM and import your save from your previous version. Prior to this guide, I downloaded the 4.0 update to Radical Red, a ROM hack for Pokemon FireRed Version; I will be importing my save from my old ROM which is on version 2.3. Note: Check the documentation for the ROM hack you wish to update to. Sometimes saves may be incompatible between versions. The documentation may have more information on how to prepare your save for updating if necessary. With all that out of way now, lets get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide: How to import your game save from another emulator to Afterplay.io</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://afterplay.io/&#34;&gt;Afterplay.io&lt;/a&gt; is a great all-purpose emulator that runs on any device with a web browser. It keeps your ROM library in sync with all your devices, even keeping saves synced so that you can resume your game on any device logged into your Afterplay account. But what if you started your game on another emulator or even on a physical cartridge? Are you doomed to just start your game over if you want to start playing the game on Afterplay? No way, josẽ! Follow this guide and you&amp;rsquo;ll learn the steps needed to be able to import your game saves into Afterplay and pick up right where you left off!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Zelda II - Adventure of Link</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zelda II: The Adventure of Link&amp;rdquo; is viewed in modern times as something of a black sheep within the beloved Legend of Zelda franchise. It’s not very hard to see why it&amp;rsquo;s thought of this way. It’s the only numbered sequel in the Legend of Zelda series. It&amp;rsquo;s not even actually called the Legend of Zelda! Just Zelda II! (This was actually a localization choice by Nintendo of America, the game is called the Legend of Zelda II in Japan)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide: How to patch a ROM on iPhone for use with Afterplay.io</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ROM Hacks are a great way to enjoy classic games in a new way. ROM Hacks can add new levels to your favorite platformer, add a brand new story to your favorite RPG, or even change the game into something new entirely. But ROM Hacks are typically distributed via patch files. Patch files can end in a variety of different extensions including but not limited to: .IPS .UPS .APS or .BPS. Patch files are not playable by themselves in emulators such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://afterplay.io/play/recently-played&#34;&gt;Afterplay.io&lt;/a&gt;. Instead they must be applied to the ROM file of the game that they were created for, generating a brand new ROM file. This processes is known as &amp;ldquo;patching&amp;rdquo;. Luckily there are tools on the web that allow us to do this patching process all from just an iPhone or iPad. Follow this guide for a step-by-step tutorial on how to patch a ROM on your phone to use on an emulator such as Afterplay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Super Mario Bros. 2</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 2 types of people in this world: those who say Super Mario Bros. 2 has two playable characters and those who say it has four. And then there is the third type of person who lives under a rock. The one who is unaware of the story of how the version of Super Mario Bros. 2 that the rest of the world got was not the Super Mario Bros. 2 that was released in Japan. Thankfully this review is for all three of you. So before we dive too deep into my thoughts on Super Mario Bros. 2, let’s go over the game’s interesting history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Legend of Zelda</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Legend of Zelda. The game with the legendary golden cartridge. If you had this game in your collection then you were legendary. You could save your game, something unknown to NES gamers at the time. Passwords and grey cartridges were for the peasants. (I don’t know who the black unlicensed TenGen carts were for&amp;hellip; witches maybe?) If you had the gold cart you had the Holy Grail. You were playground royalty.
&lt;img alt=&#34;The gold cart was such a big deal that Nintendo even cut a hole in the cardboard packaging to show it off&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog4/image1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YOU Should be Backing up Your Game Collection</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someday the last NES or SEGA or Playstation will stop working but thanks to digital game preservation we will be able to enjoy these games for generations. This has taken various forms in the past, most notably the Wii’s Virtual Console, followed up by the 3DS and WiiU&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Console, as well as re-releases in various compilations and collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;I can hear the Wii Shop Channel music in my head as I reminisce about browsing for Virtual Console titles to purchase&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog3/image1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Super Mario Bros.</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What can be said about Super Mario Bros. that hasn’t already been said. It&amp;rsquo;s probably THE video game. If you asked any random person off the street to name a video game title; even (or especially) if they had never played a video game before, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that “Super Mario” would come out of their mouth. It&amp;rsquo;s only one of the greatest selling games of all time. (A fact, no doubt helped by it being a pack-in title with almost every NES sold after 1986.) Some consider it the game that saved the US home console market after the US video game crash of 1983. It wasn’t the first side-scrolling platform game. But when it came out; it was the game that defined what a platformer should look like. Super Mario Bros. was the game all future side scrollers tried to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide: How to play Donkey Kong Country Returns without Motion Controls</title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/blog/1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First published in 2022: For readers in 2025 you can also play Donkey Kong Country Returns without motion controls by purchasing &amp;ldquo;Donkey Kong Country Returns HD&amp;rdquo; for Nintendo Switch. Now back to your originally scheduled programming&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Not my Donkey Kong Country!&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kmstrube.net/images/blog1/image1.jpg&#34;&gt;
I recently purchased Donkey Kong Country Returns for the Wii from my local game shop. I had played the 3DS port before and beat it all the way through but I thought that the original version deserved its place on my shelf next to the WiiU version of DKC Tropical Freeze. I knew that the original had motion controls unlike Tropical Freeze which controls brilliantly with the WiiU Gamepad or Pro Controller. I decided to give it a go and found the Wiimote turned to its side and the tacked on motion control just to do something as simple as roll simply would not do. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the Donkey Kong I remembered on my Super Nintendo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.kmstrube.net/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kmstrube.net/resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.two-column {
  display: flex;
  gap: 2rem;
  flex-wrap: wrap;
}

.column {
  flex: 1 1 45%;
  min-width: 250px;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;kasey-strube&#34;&gt;Kasey Strube&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-and-network-professional&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;IT and Network Professional&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;two-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phone: [Redacted]&lt;br&gt;
Email: [Redacted]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website: [Redacted]&lt;br&gt;
Address: [Redacted]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
IT Professional with 12  years of experience working with Business, Residential, and Government customers as well as 6 years in the Financial Services industry. I have experience installing and maintaining Business Telephone Systems, Hosted PBX systems, Closed Circuit Camera Surveillance Systems, Home and Business Security Alarm Systems, and Windows 2012/2016/2019 Domains and Linux Servers. I have managed and migrated 80+ user systems from on-premises to Microsoft 365/Azure Cloud.
&lt;div class=&#34;two-column&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
